

Front-End Developer

864-449-7072 frazierr2@gmail.com ThinkFrazier.com github/frazierr2

Objective

I am a Front-End Developer with over 7 years' experience in Tech Support, System Integrations and Corporate Training along with 2 and a half years' experience in full-time Web Development. Passionate about shaping the future of the web, I am seeking a position that will allow me to create web apps and websites that are geared to the end user. I strive to understand the user who will be using the application inside and out to provide a clean and positive experience.

RELEVANTSKILLS

LANGUAGE AND PRACTICES

HTML5

CSS3/SCSS

JavaScript (ES5 and ES6)

Git

JSON

AJAX

RESTful API's

Github / Bitbucket

PHP

SOL

AWS

FRAMEWORKS AND LIBRARIES

React / Vue

Backbone JS/Underscore JS

Bootstrap / UI Kit

iQuery

Laravel

CURRENT PROJECT

Over the last few months, I have transitioned to a Full Stack Developer with Jackson Furniture. With a few full stack apps under my belt, I have been developing tools and reports for internal departments to cut cost, run more efficiently and complete more task.

Outside of work, I have been leveling up with PHP, SQL and other backend technologies so that I can continue to develop and grow as a full stack developer.

EDUCATION

Front-End Engineering

The Iron Yard, September 2016 - December 2016

Bachelors of Science in Business

Administration and Sociology

Winthrop University, August 2004 - May 2009

WORK EXPERIENCE

Front-End Developer

Jackson Furniture

July 2017 - present

- Complete redesign and overhaul of Jackson Furniture's website using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and PHP to create a responsive site for any device that you are on.
- During redesign, used AJAX to communicate to a PHP Laravel backend to bring all products and data into view from a SQL/DB2 databases.
- Work with PHP and Python teams to create and manage web apps for internal user teams and for our external dealer portals.
- Refactor and reduce existing code base from 12 companywide sites down to three across all platforms.
- Develop backend code in Laravel to handle and manipulate data.
- Creating SQL queries to add, delete, update and manipulate data with our schemas and tables.
- -Starting to transition frontend to Vue.js

Front-End Developer

MedProcure, LLC

March 2017 - July 2017

- Contracted to design, develop and implement the front end of their new Supply Chain Management Software.
- Combining HTML5, CSS3, Vanilla JavaScript and jQuery, I created the front end for their meal planning application where schools can offer to parents as a nutritional resource.
- Using AJAX, I communicated with a PHP Backend to pull in all data to view and manipulate based on user interaction.